{
    "questions": [
        {
            "id": "1",
            "question": "If (c^4) * (c^5)^3 = c^x , what is the value of x?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "17",
                "39",
                "29",
                "20"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "29",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "First simplify the expression, (c^4) * c^(5*3) to c^4 * c^15 = c^(4+15) = c^19.",
            "difficulty": 4
        },
        {
            "id": "2",
            "question": "The expression ( (1/3)^(-3) + 4^0 ) evaluates to what value?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "29",
                "28",
                "2",
                "1"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "29",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "The definition of negative exponent inverts the base, making (1/3)^(-3) into 3^3, or 27. 4^0 is always 1, so the total is 28.",
            "difficulty": 3
        },
        {
            "id": "3",
            "question": "Which of the following expressions is equivalent to ((a^5)^3 * a^(-15)) for all a \u2260 0?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "0",
                "1",
                "a^6",
                "a^10"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "1",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "The expression simplifies to a^(5*3) * a^(-15) = a^(15+(-15)) = a^0 , and any non-zero number to the power of 0 is always 1.",
            "difficulty": 4
        },
        {
            "id": "4",
            "question": "Which of the following expressions is equivalent to (3x^2 z^20)^4?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "81x^8 z^80",
                "12x^8 z^80",
                "36x^8 z^80",
                "81x^8 z^100"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "81x^8 z^80",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "The expression simplifies to (3^4)(x^(2*4))(z^(20*4)) = 81x^8 z^80.",
            "difficulty": 3
        },
        {
            "id": "5",
            "question": "If d \u2260 0, what is the value of the expression -(6d)^0 + 8^1 - 3^2?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "-8",
                "4",
                "-4",
                "8"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "-4",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "The expression simplifies to -(6d)^0 + 8 - 9 = -1 + 8 - 9 = -2.",
            "difficulty": 4
        },
        {
            "id": "6",
            "question": "Which of the following expressions is equivalent to ((m^2)^5 * m^(-30)) for all m \u2260 0?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "1",
                "m^10",
                "0",
                "m^5"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "1",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "The expression simplifies to m^(2*5) * m^(-30) = m^(10-30) = m^0 , and any non-zero number to the power of 0 is always 1.",
            "difficulty": 4
        },
        {
            "id": "7",
            "question": "The expression ( (1/5)^(-4) + 5^0 ) evaluates to what value?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "625",
                "626",
                "624",
                "525"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "626",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "The definition of negative exponent inverts the base, making (1/5)^(-4) into 5^4, or 625. 5^0 is always 1, so the total is 626.",
            "difficulty": 3
        },
        {
            "id": "8",
            "question": "(y^7 * (y^5)^4 = y^x) for all y \u2260 0? What is the value of x?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "46",
                "45",
                "27",
                "20"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "27",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "The expression simplifies into y^7 * y^(5*4) = y^(7+20) = y^27.",
            "difficulty": 4
        },
        {
            "id": "9",
            "question": "Which expression is equivalent to (4x^3 z^30)^5?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "1024x^15 z^150",
                "1024x^15 z^120",
                "3048x^15 z^100",
                "1024x^15 z^100"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "1024x^15 z^150",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "The expression simplifies into (4^5)(x^(3*5))(z^(30*5)) = 1024x^15 z^150.",
            "difficulty": 3
        },
        {
            "id": "10",
            "question": "If p \u2260 0, what is the value of - (8p)^0 + 9^1 - 4^2?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "1",
                "0",
                "-1",
                "2"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "-1",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "The expression simplifies into -1+9-16 = -8.",
            "difficulty": 4
        },
        {
            "id": "11",
            "question": "Which of the following expressions is equivalent to ((b^2)^5 * b^(-20)) for all b \u2260 0?",
            "type": "multiple_choice",
            "options": [
                "1",
                "b^10",
                "0",
                "b^5"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "1",
            "whyCorrectAnswer": "The expression simplifies to b^(2*5) * b^(-20) = b^(10-20) = b^0 , and any non-zero number to the power of 0 is always 1.",
            "difficulty": 4
        }
    ]
}